[Genius Girlfriend]
[Episode 17]
What's wrong, bro? Tired?
Yes.
Let's take a taxi back.
Tired after just this much?
Hey, I have to say,
it's really a beautiful sunny day.
Yeah.
So beautiful.
Shen Fuxuan's so annoying,
suddenly uncontactable.
He just ditched us like that.
Right, so disloyal.
With all these bags and bundles,
we could really
use a pair of strong hands right now.
We brought too many snacks.
♪ I'm like the gentle clouds in the sky ♪
Let's eat them up quickly.
Don't worry with Duan Qiyan here.
They'll be gone in no time.
Give me a break.
What's wrong with you two?
♪ Looking forward
to the stop of the night breeze ♪
Not helping the girls
carry anything?
Give it to me.
♪ I'm wandering about carefully,
looking for the answer ♪
Thanks.
Give it to me.
Layer up when going up the mountain later.
It's cold there.
Okay.
Alright.
♪ Sometimes I wonder
if I should back down ♪
Hurry up!
Hurry, hurry.
♪ Sudden alienation between us
is what scares me the most ♪
♪ How can two hearts beat as one
and truly feel each other? ♪
♪ The meteors fly past,
silencing thoughts ♪
♪ Please, give me some clues ♪
♪ I hope you can see through
my situation and confusion ♪
♪ And save me ♪
♪ Can you hear me? Why won't you answer? ♪
♪ I'm calling you secretly at night ♪
♪ The moon whispers
fond words by my ears ♪
♪ It asks if you're still there
through ups and downs ♪
3, 2, 1.
Turn it on!
♪ Am I lying? I answer my own questions ♪
Nice.
♪ But I've already fallen,
I can't help it, oh ♪
Happy graduation!
♪ Forgive me for being silly
for you and only you ♪
The stars are so bright today.
♪ My desires turn into ocean waves
in my dreams, lapping gently ♪
It'll be even more beautiful tomorrow.
This trip of ours
-is totally worth it!
-He's lost it.
What's wrong?
I was thinking about how
Shen Fuxuan hasn't contacted us all day.
I'm worried if something happened to him.
Don't worry.
He's probably off
having fun by himself.
But why'd he ignore our texts?
Could Shen Fuxuan
have some other reason?
He isn't usually like this.
Actually,
I know the reason.
He contacted me earlier.
He gave me a letter
and said
that if we see a meteor shower,
I should read it to everyone for him.
What meteor shower?
Just read it now.
Read it now?
Go ahead. It's fine.
Hello,
my dear friends.
At this moment,
you must be on the mountain top,
having made wishes while watching
the meteor shower streak across
the vast starry sky.
It's a pity
that I couldn't
spend this moment with you,
because I'm currently abroad,
preparing for the new semester
of a five-year medical program
my parents arranged.
He went abroad?
Shen really kept this secret airtight—
not a peep leaked.
I'm sorry for
not telling you this news in person,
because I really didn't know
how to say goodbye to you all.
I'm used to being on my own my whole life.
Expressing my feelings
is harder for me
than calculus.
So I can only
write these things down here.
You're the ones
I find hardest to part with.
You're the friends
I'll miss the most.
You probably have no idea
how lucky
someone like me feels
to be treated as one of you.
So, thank you
for letting a buzzkill and loner
like me
become a part of your youth.
Being friends with you is
the best thing that's happened to me.
I'm leaving.
Please make a wish
upon a shooting star for me too:
let Shen Fuxuan come back sooner;
don't let him always eat alone;
may our friendship last forever.
Shen really just left like that.
What's with all the long faces?
Communication is so advanced now.
Even if he's abroad,
it's very easy to stay in touch.
Exactly. Being far from home is nice too.
Nobody died.
Yeah.
But since we met Shen,
we've never really
been apart for a long time.
Just thinking about how
we'll be separated soon for a few years
is pretty depressing.
Shen Fuxuan is actually
very suited to be a doctor.
He's rigorous,
conscientious,
calm, and has an inquisitive mind.
He will be a great doctor.
So we should be happy for him.
Exactly.
Don't be sad.
Yeah, don't be sad over nothing.
You babies.
This is nothing.
You're just a year older than us.
But I'm a college student,
and you're high schoolers.
Then Mr. College Student,
tell us what's so different about college.
Once in college,
you'll find that everything changes.
Your horizons will broaden.
And you'll no longer be a kid.
From the moment
you get your acceptance letter,
you'll experience all kinds of goodbyes.
For the first time,
you'll part with your family,
with childhood friends,
and with your familiar hometown.
You'll be in an unfamiliar city,
looking at unfamiliar faces.
You've to face all of this.
Why do we have to grow up?
Why can't we stay together forever?
Growing up is inevitable.
But I think
our friendship can remain unchanged.
As long as we hold on,
we can always be together.
Right.
Don't be afraid of goodbyes.
But learn to cherish
every present moment.
Makes sense.
But...
Don't you think what he just said
sounds a bit like someone?
Like who?
Um, um...
-Director Sui!
-Yes, I think so too!
-What? No way.
I was just going to say that.
Impossible, absolutely impossible.
To be honest, it is a bit patronizing.
Come on, let's toast.
Cheers.
To Shen Fuxuan.
-Shen Fuxuan, you've got this!
-To Shen Fuxuan!
Go for it!
Zeqiu,
look how bright that star is.
Which one's the brightest?
I think that one's very bright.
That one's bright too.
That star...
You're awake too.
Do you want to
go for a walk?
Why are you still up?
Can't sleep?
Not exactly.
I'm just excited about
camping with friends.
What about you? Why can't you sleep?
I was drawing comics.
Drawing comics?
I'm recording every
important moment of ours
in comics.
I'll show you when I get the chance.
What's that,
that green thing?
Where?
There.
This one?
It's so pretty.
It looks like an emerald.
Any stone in your hands
would become a gem.
It must've been polished over time
to have such a perfect shape.
For you.
Why give it to me?
Because I want to.
If you don't want it,
give it back.
I'll ask if anyone else wants it.
Of course I want it.
Are you feeling better now?
I'm just a bit sad
that I didn't get to say goodbye
to Shen Fuxuan in person.
What if
it was Duan Qiyan or someone else
who left this time?
I'd feel the same.
We're all buddies.
What if it was me?
You're different.
Aren't... Aren't we all buddies?
Do you know about the binary star system?
Binary star system?
It means two stars have their own orbits
but revolve around the same center.
Duan Qiyan and the rest are my buddies,
but you're more like
my binary star partner.
We'll move forward along different orbits,
but our center will
always be the same.
The binary star system in astrophysics
is a fascinating interstellar system.
Two stars have their own orbits,
revolving around the same center.
They never conflict
and never part ways.
I also have my own binary star partner,
so I'll never be lonely
in the vast universe.
Thank you, my binary star partner,
Jiang Yubai.
What are you looking at,
so absorbed?
Look at these two little flowers.
How special.
On some random day, the two seeds
must've been blown here by the wind.
In this field of pink muhly grass,
they grew together
towards the sun.
This pink muhly field is like a universe.
And these two are lives from afar,
swaying together
in the long river of time.
Don't they look like
a perfect symbiotic function?
Mutually dependent
variables with
completely overlapping domains,
where f(x, y) equals zero.
Without either one,
this formula wouldn't exist.
Using a formula to describe two flowers...
is quite novel.
I feel like all relationships
can be expressed with functions.
Friendship is like a composite function:
you need me, and I need you;
nested together,
we jointly produce a more interesting
and better range.
A passing encounter
with a stranger is like
a probability density function:
at a certain point in time and space,
the probability of our meeting
is no longer zero,
and then quickly returns to zero.
We...
You two,
stop chatting
and come help!
Hurry!
Let's go.
Coming.
Jiang Yubai, come,
help me with the table.
Alright.
Duan Qiyan and I will go
wash the pots and vegetables.
He has too much energy anyway.
Let's go.
Wait, wait.
My delicate hands
can't do that kind of work.
Stop the nonsense and come now.
Fine. Stop pulling me.
Should I bring
the table and tableware over?
Okay.
Hey, bring the cassette stove over.
I'll go get it.
Okay.
Why are you so bad at everything?
Can't even wash vegetables properly?
I didn't do it on purpose!
If you think I'm stupid and ridiculous,
then stay away from me!
What's with that girl?
What did I do to deserve this?
Attention, everyone.
I think we can play a game.
Only the winners of this game
get to eat. How about it?
What game?
This game's very simple.
I'll explain the rules.
First, we'll close our eyes.
I'll count down from 3,
and then we'll all
open our eyes at the same time.
If two people's eyes meet,
they'll be the winners
of the round of the game.
Of course,
if a third person
makes eye contact with
either of you two,
it won't count as a win.
Alright, got it? It's very simple.
You'd be a fool to not get it.
Come on.
Everyone, close your eyes.
Okay, I got it.
Yeah? Close your eyes.
Right.
Close your eyes. Good.
3, 2, 1.
Open your eyes!
Wait.
I looked at her.
Right. Jiang looked at you, Zhixia.
Again.
T-This doesn't count as a win.
Come on, again.
Close your eyes.
3, 2, 1.
Open your eyes!
Your eyes met?
Yes, the two of us.
Who did you look at?
You didn't look at them, right?
Right, she didn't.
Okay, you two won.
You can eat!
If we didn't see it,
that means we made eye contact.
Yes. Go on, eat up.
-They won. Let's continue.
-It smells so good!
I'm so hungry.
No use in complaining. Ignore them.
We need to eat too.
Close your eyes!
3, 2, 1.
Open your eyes!
Our eyes met.
I looked at Lin Zeqiu.
Stop looking at him. What's there to see?
You ruined our chance to eat!
Again!
Eat slowly. Leave some food for us.
Come on.
Close your eyes.
3, 2, 1.
Let's go!
Yummy, right?
Yummy.
You looked at me, huh?
Last round.
I'm at my limit.
-No, there must be winners.
-It's delicious.
This game has no end.
It has, for sure.
Come on, close your eyes.
3, 2, 1.
Open your eyes!
You two look at each other. Let's eat.
Don't mind them.
You two keep looking.
I'll have one.
Who wants some Coke?
-Me, me!
-Me too.
Slow down.
Here, have a fishball.
Thanks.
Zeqiu... it's overflowing.
Zeqiu, have one too.
Delicious.
Then...
g-give me one too.
This fishball's r-really delicious.
It has fish roe inside.
Is it good?
It's good. Try it while it's hot.
Here.
Thanks.
-It's delicious.
-Thank you.
It's nothing special.
Give it to me then.
It's so good.
-Look at my jellyfish.
-Eat your jellyfish.
This jellyfish took me a lot of effort.
What are you doing?
Tingting, are you full?
Are you on a diet again?
You've been dieting every day this year,
but you're still the same.
I'm not going to see the meteor shower.
You all go without me.
W-Wait, Tang,
I was just joking.
What I meant is
your figure's already perfect.
You're so thin.
Why diet?
You have no weight to lose.
You're great.
You're excellent.
Duan Qiyan, shut up for a moment.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I just don't want to go anymore.
Tingting, is something on your mind?
I don't want to make a wish.
Even if I make one,
it won't come true.
Why won't it come true?
I want to go to Qingbei University,
but I know I won't make it.
So my wish won't come true.
What if it affects your wishes too?
I don't want to drag you down.
What are you laughing at? I'm serious!
I don't want to bring you bad luck.
That's such a wild thought.
Don't think like that.
Tang, let me help you out with that.
How about this?
Don't wish for Qingbei.
Wish for Zhendan.
It's not like Qingbei is the only
university in the world.
Just wish for Zhendan.
It will come true.
Then when you all get into Qingbei,
I'll be the only one at Zhendan.
I'll drift further and further
away from you,
and our friendship will fade.
What if in the future,
we completely lose touch?
We won't.
Didn't you say that
we're friends filtered over time?
You need us,
and we need you too.
Because of you,
we started listening to music,
going to concerts,
and doing lots of fun things.
Yeah.
We even did a performance because of you.
These are wonderful memories we share.
We won't drift apart
because of physical distance.
Tang,
think about it.
We grew up together.
Will our friendship fade
just because we're apart
for a mere four years?
You're underestimating
our friendship.
We've been partners in crime
since we were little.
Once you graduate and come to Huacheng,
I'll take you out to turn the place
upside down.
Who's your partner in crime?
Get lost.
Okay.
He rolled into our tent.
Rolled into the wrong place.
Roll back here.
I'm a little dizzy.
Show-off.
-Let's eat.
-Come on.
Let's have a drink.
To friendship.
Come on.
-Come on.
-Cheers!
Cheers!
I'm coming!
Oh my goodness.
I bounced up.
Are you just bad at this or faking it?
Why aren't you hanging out with them?
Let me! I'll help you.
They're so childish.
Childish?
Coming from you?
Aren't you in the same class?
Did you forget we're the same age?
Right, we're the same age.
I forgot.
Look who's talking.
You're just
a year older than your sister.
So worried about
your sister coming out to play that
you had to tag along?
It's not that I don't trust her.
Stand there in one spot.
It's just that hanging out with you all
is actually pretty fun.
Start.
Even though sometimes I don't join in,
it's still pretty fun
just watching from the side.
Actually, all my life,
I've rarely participated
in group activities.
But now I feel that
as long as I stay with them,
I'm very satisfied.
Stop playing!
Come back and help!
Come down!
Coming! Let's go.
It's 9 PM. The meteor shower's coming.
Let's guess who
will spot the first shooting star.
I predict
I'll be the first to catch one.
Stop guessing.
You suck but still love to compete.
With your short attention span,
you think you'll be first?
Is that one?
That's an airplane.
Is that it?
That's over the sea, Duan Qiyan.
That's a lighthouse.
Shooting stars don't look like that.
What about that?
That's a flying spark.
Give it a rest.
You almost set me on fire.
Zeqiu, there hasn't been a shooting star.
Are you stressed?
I'm not stressed.
You have to trust
your brother's professionalism.
Besides, even weather forecasts
are wrong sometimes.
Don't be anxious. Give it a minute.
I remember when we watched them
at the astronomy club,
there were usually
only one or two at first.
But then they became meteor showers.
Really stunning.
Yeah.
It hasn't reached
the peak of the meteor shower yet.
Waiting for a shooting star,
you have to be sincere.
Be truly sincere
from the bottom of your heart.
Should we tell
the shooting stars our wishes
to summon them?
I'll go first. I have one in mind.
Lord Shooting Star!
I want to get into Zhendan!
I also want to become super pretty.
And super rich.
It'd be best if I could also
become Han Geng's manager.
And I want to travel around the world!
Hold it, hold it.
Your self-introduction
is so long-winded, Tang.
By then, your self-introduction
will be famous Zhendan alumnus,
beautiful, rich woman,
and Han Geng's manager—Tang Tingting.
Wait, there's an addendum:
traveling around the world.
Duan Qiyan,
the shooting stars are watching.
You'd better watch your mouth,
or it might not bless you.
Look at my big mouth.
Um, Lord Shooting Star,
I was just joking!
Just showing off a bit of my own humor.
Um,
don't mind me.
Hey,
Zeqiu.
Tell us
how many shooting stars you can catch
and what wishes you'll make.
Catch shooting stars?
Am I a cop?
Shooting Star,
I want to always
be able to see the person I want to see.
Who's that?
There are many people I want to see.
Jin Baihui.
What's your wish?
I...
Hello, Shooting Star!
I want to be a little further from home!
What's with that look?
Isn't it good to be further from home?
That way I can be with you all.
I got into Qingbei.
Surely my parents won't pressure me
to study anymore, right?
That's right.
Jiang Yubai,
your shooting star can't hear you
if you just whisper to it.
I want to go to Qingbei University
with Lin Zhixia.
I'm not done yet, Zeqiu.
I want to stargaze with Zeqiu.
I also want to play ball with Duan Qiyan.
I want to hit the library with Jin Baihui.
And share life stories
with Tang Tingting
and Shen Fuxuan.
Your wishes sound
so heartwarming and lovely.
Maybe everyone thinks
I have a lot of friends.
But actually,
I've been constantly transferring schools
and changing environments,
often parting ways right after
getting to know my classmates.
I haven't had any deep friendships.
So,
I'm very glad to have met you all.
Zeqiu and I had a rough start.
At that time, I thought
he was bullying Lin Zhixia.
I didn't expect him to be her brother.
Duan Qiyan, Jin Baihui.
If it weren't for
the competition prep with you,
I'd never have fought to the end.
Tang Tingting, if it weren't for you,
I really wouldn't have had the chance
to help the police solve a case.
And to Shen Fuxuan,
who's far away overseas:
if it weren't for you,
I wouldn't have known that so many people
would have my back that day.
The most important one is Lin Zhixia.
We went through
many important moments in life together.
Maybe even you don't know,
but it's because I met you
that I could have so many
wonderful stories and beautiful bonds
with everyone.
And because of you all,
my night sky has become even brighter.
So...
What are those?
I made these yesterday
using petals from the sea of flowers.
In case we don't see
a shooting star today,
it can serve as a keepsake.
This way, when everyone sees this,
it'll feel as if
we're right next to each other.
And each bottle contains
a different flower,
each conveying a different meaning.
I won't elaborate.
Look it up yourselves when you go back.
Here.
Yours, Duan Qiyan.
Thanks.
-Tang Tingting, yours.
-Thank you.
Jin Baihui, yours.
Thank you.
Zeqiu.
This is yours.
So pretty.
What's yours?
It even has my name.
Maple leaves?
-Pink flowers.
-What's yours? Let me see.
It's already 9:30 PM.
About time a shooting star appear.
I don't know.
Will we get to see one tonight?
It's okay.
Why don't we play something,
or...
does anyone have snacks?
I'm hungry.
I have some food here.
I have some.
There are snacks here. Come on.
I'll add some firewood!
Maybe after today,
we'll never be in the same city anymore.
♪ Only for this lingering warmth
of the moment ♪
We might not see each other
for a long time.
Everyone traveled a long, long way
♪ Trading souls with the night ♪
just to make a wish upon you.
Please don't leave everyone with regrets.
♪ Every dusk I have stolen ♪
Please, you must appear.
♪ Foretells a parting ♪
Please.
This one!
It's super yummy.
Let me see.
Why's there so little left?
♪ Where did the storm start brewing ♪
What's that?
-A shooting star!
Shooting stars! Hurry!
-Hurry! Hurry!
-Shooting stars!
♪ Drenching you before we knew it? ♪
Shooting stars!
Hurry, hurry!
Shooting stars! Shooting stars!
Shooting stars!
♪ Let me draw near to you ♪
They're so beautiful.
So pretty.
♪ Let me imagine you ♪
♪ Let me sink into your ♪
♪ Scattered golden glow ♪
♪ Let the night blur your figure ♪
Right, make a wish!
Make a wish now!
♪ Yet tear myself away from you ♪
Make one for Shen Fuxuan first.
May our friendship
-last forever!
-Last forever!
♪ I can't fathom why ♪
One more, hurry!
♪ I've never truly possessed you ♪
Make a wish.
Huacheng, here I come!
♪ That blazing, radiant feeling ♪
When I get there, I will make my mark!
♪ Once the rain stops, clouds disperse ♪
There's no time.
Everyone make your own wish.
Hurry!
♪ Hence, time and again, I lose ♪
I want to take good care
of the people around me,
especially my parents
and my little sister.
♪ Myself ♪
♪ Draw near to you ♪
♪ Let me imagine you ♪
Oh heavens, all gods and immortals,
please bless me so I don't fall behind.
♪ Let me sink into your ♪
♪ Scattered golden glow ♪
I hope I can truly be myself one day.
♪ Let the night blur your figure ♪
♪ Yet tear myself away from you ♪
♪ I can't fathom why ♪
I, Duan Qiyan,
must make my mark in Huacheng.
♪ I've never truly possessed you ♪
I hope there comes a day
when Lin Zhixia understands...
♪ That blazing, radiant feeling ♪
♪ Once the rain stops, clouds disperse ♪
♪ The rarest blessing in life
is a sweet dream ♪
♪ That never ends ♪
Are you done making wishes?
I suggest
we take a group photo right here,
leaving a spot for Shen,
to mark our visit.
-Okay.
-Okay!
I'll get the camera.
It's counting down. Hurry.
Come on. 3, 2, 1.
[Intercity Bus:
Xiaochongshan to Ougang]
Get your luggage!
Don't you want to learn skateboarding?
I'll take you tomorrow.
Sure.
But I'm afraid of falling.
I'll borrow protective gear for you,
so it won't hurt if you fall.
Come find me early tomorrow.
Keep the emerald safe.
Thank you for the emerald.
[Ougang City
Public Security Bureau Summons]
Your P2P lending
has collapsed.
The boss of the head office has run away.
What about the money?
They took it all.
Over 2 billion in total.
They took it all?
Yes.
Just the amount sold from you
is over 2.2 million.
2,276,500.
You can't escape joint criminal liability.
And your final sentence
still depends on how cooperative you are
with our investigation.
You must actively return all illegal gains
and try your best
to compensate all the clients
under your name for their losses.
Try to earn their forgiveness.
Hello?
Say something.
What's wrong?
Did something happen to our son?
No.
Our son's fine.
It's...
I-It's me.
I...
I need to discuss something with you.
What is it? Go on.
Can...
Can you...
lend me two million?
I was cheated by the company.
The boss ran away.
It's too much, right?
Never mind. It's fine.
Then...
one million is also fine.
Or even less.
500... 500,000, okay?
500,000 works too.
Anything's fine.
Guan Xunmei,
I haven't had time to tell you,
but all my money is
tied up in real estate.
My company went bust too.
I really can't help you.
Do you need me to take our son?
But in my current situation,
it's really hard for me to take him.
-Let's go home for dinner.
-Bye.
-Bye-bye.
See you tomorrow.
Bye-bye.
[5 missed calls from Mom]
Mom.
Why are the lights off?
I called you back later.
Why didn't you answer?
Mom?
Mom!
When I waved and told Jiang Yubai
I'd see him tomorrow,
I thought I was just solving
a math problem with clear steps.
"See you tomorrow" was a constant.
I'd see him like I always did.
We'd do many things together.
We'd see each other millions of times.
But after I grew up, I learned that
encounters between people
aren't linear equations.
There are no fixed slopes and intercepts.
They're more like points scattered
at random, governed by probability.
Every reunion
takes a great deal of luck.
And my luck seems to have run out.
After that parting,
my best friend, Jiang Yubai...
disappeared from my world again.